[ Music ]
[音乐]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning.
&gt;&gt; 早上好
My name is Josh.
我是 Josh
And I'm part of the Technology
我是来自 Apple
Evangelism team at Apple.
技术传播团队的一员
Our team has the incredible
我们的团队非常荣幸
honor of working with
能与来自世界各地的
developers, like you, from all
像你们一样的
around the world.
开发者合作
And our goal is to help you
我们的目标是帮助你
create truly great apps.
创造真正优秀的 App
And in these conversations with
在与你们的对话中
you, we learn so much.
我们学到了很多
We gain an understanding of the
我们了解到了
processes you take; the
你工作的过程
challenges, goals, and
你面临的挑战 目标
aspirations that you have.
和你的抱负
We learn about the tricks and
我们也学习到了那些
tools that help you out, and
帮你走出困境的技巧和技能
then those that hinder.
也了解了你的困难
And although every story that we
尽管我们听到的每个故事
hear is a little different,
都有一些不同
there's an incredible number of
但是大家身上
common threads no matter which
也有着诸多共通之处
part of the world the story
无论你来自何方
Now, when you think about craft
当我们提到“craft”（手艺）这个词
you probably first think about
你最先想到的可能是设计
But as developers and engineers,
但作为开发者和工程师
we craft, too.
我们同样也有“手艺”
After all, craft is defined as
毕竟手艺的定义是
skill in planning, making, and
计划 制作和执行的技能
It's to create or produce
它也是用细心 技巧和独创性
something with care, skill, or
来创造和生产的过程
Codes written by hand.
我们用双手书写代码
It involves incredible skill.
它对技巧的要求也很高
And there's an ingenuity to the
在我们搭建 App 时
technique that we take.
我们使用的技巧
The choices that we make when
我们做出的选择
building an app.
都是具有独创性的
And I want to talk to you today
今天我想和大家谈谈
about that craft and care, to
手艺和细心
bring care into your code, into
将它们融入到你的代码
your storyboards and into your
你的 Storyboards
products.
和你的产品中
This might seem easy at first.
一开始这似乎很简单
But with all of the demands on
但是 作为当今的开发者
us, as developers today, this
我们面临着各种各样的需求
can sometimes be quite hard.
这有时会非常困难
Skill with a given craft is
特定技能是随着时间的推移
something that develops over
而发展起来的
time.
这需要奉献 耐心
and focus.
和专注
It's about learning to enjoy the
学习享受
process of getting there almost
到达目的的过程
as much as the destination
就像享受目的本身一样
itself.
现在 过程的一部分
also about converting those
也包括把那些可能
things that might take intense
一开始需要
and conscious focus at first,
集中注意力的事情
into habits.
转变成习惯
Similar to driving, with
与开车相似
experience and practice, the
随着经验和实践的积累
number of things that we have to
我们在开车时
consciously focus on while we're
必须有意识地关注的事情
driving reduces over time
会随着时间的推移而减少
because we convert things to
因为我们把它转变成了
natural, automatic habits.
自然的 自动的习惯
And we can do the same thing
我们可以在 App 开发中
with app development.
达到同样的效果
And to do this, it means
要做到这一点
developing great habits, as
就意味着培养良好的习惯
opposed to poor ones.
而不是坏习惯
When it comes to building an
当涉及到构建一个 App 时
app, there's a lot of details to
有很多细节需要注意
pay attention to and as a
作为一个开发者
developer, so many of these
我们需要关注
details that we have to care
很多的细节
about, well, they're rarely
然而这些努力
actually directly seen by the
可能很少会被用户
customers who use our apps.
直接看到
And yet, they can be felt in
然而 它们可以
such significant ways, impacting
以重要的形式被感觉到
performance, reliability, and
影响性能 可靠性
stability.
和稳定性
And so, there's a lot of
其实 细节很多
details.
只是没有足够的时间
to focus on them all.
去全部关注到
So, I'd like to spend some time
今天我想花点时间
today reviewing some practices
回顾一下一些实践
that can hopefully inform and
这些实践可能会丰富
enrich our work as developers,
作为开发者的我们
things for us to work towards
的工作内容
integrating into our regular
让我们可以将它们整合到
workflows, such that they just
我们的常规工作流程中
become habit and automatic.
形成主动的习惯
This will save us frustration,
这样我们可以避免挫折
hassle, and waste of time down
省去麻烦和节约时间
the road.
对于你们中的许多人
you're already doing many of
我相信你们已经在做
these things.
这些事情了
But perhaps there are some that
但也许有些人
haven't yet fully become habits
还没有完全
for you.
形成习惯
And maybe you'll be inspired to
也许你会受到启发
practice them more.
加强练习
So, first, let's get organized.
首先 让我们梳理一下
In addition to being an app
除了是一名 App 开发者
developer, I'm also a
我还是一个木工
I find that it's this great
我觉得对我而言
escape from the modern-day world
这是逃离现代世界的
for me.
一个很好的方式
But one thing that's for certain
但有一件事是肯定的
is that beautiful, well-crafted
漂亮的 精致的家具
furniture, is much easier to
一定出自
build in a clean shop.
干净整洁的商店
So, if your bench is cluttered
所以 如果你的工作台杂乱不堪
and poorly organized, it's hard
摆放混乱
to find the tools and materials
就很难找到你
that you need as you work along.
工作时需要的工具和材料
You constantly just have to
你必须不断地
shuffle things around to make
把东西挪来挪去
room for the work that you're
为你正在做的工作
actually doing.
腾出空间
And, in short, everything takes
简而言之 每件事都比它
so much longer than it should,
应该花费的时间要长得多
and more accidents and mistakes
在这个过程中会发生更多的
happen along the way.
事故和错误
Our team sees a lot of Xcode
我们的团队每年都
projects each year.
会看到很多 Xcode 项目
And there's definitely some
当然 保持你的工作区
practices that can help you make
干净整洁
sure that your work space is
有很多的办法
clean, tidy, and in a great
能找到激发你
position to allow you to do your
最佳工作表现的
absolute best work.
合适位置
Xcode projects benefit from
Xcode 受益于
structure and organization using
基于群组的结构和组织
This makes it so much easier at
这使得查看 App 中
a glance to see the files
每个部分中的文件
involved in each section of your
变得非常容易
application.
当你要修复 Bug 时
when you're trying to fix a bug.
它可以帮助你快速实现
Groups are best used to organize
群组最适合
your project functionally in a
从功能上组织你的项目
way that logically follows how
这种方式可以遵循用户与 App
someone might interact with your
潜在的进行交互的方式
We often see projects that are
我们经常看到
organized by file type or maybe
按文件类型分类的项目
just don't use groups at all.
或者根本不使用群组
And that doesn't really help
当人们随后
someone out later when they're
想要快速理解这些
quickly trying to understand how
原文件之间的关联时
all of these source files relate
这样并不能真正帮助人们
to each other.
解决问题
Furthermore, it can really help
此外 如果你能确保
project structure and your file
相互匹配
system structure actually match
将会非常有帮助
Since Xcode 9, when you create a
自 Xcode 9 起
new group inside of your
当你在项目中创建新群组
project, it actually also
它也会在磁盘上
creates a folder on disk to
创建一个文件夹
house the files that you place
来存放你
inside of that group.
该组中的文件
This means when you're looking
这意味着当你
at your project in source
在源代码控制中查看项目时
control, or just browsing the
或者只是浏览文件系统时
file system, the structure is
结构是镜像的
mirrored, and this will really
这会切实帮助你
help you reduce confusion and
减少日后的
missteps later on.
混淆和错误
Storyboards are an incredibly
Storyboards 是一个
powerful tool for building out
非常强大的工具
user interfaces in a visual
可以用可视化的方式构建用户界面
manner.
但我们确实
projects that build out their
遇到过很多项目
entire UI in a single
它们将整个 UI 构建在
storyboard.
一个 Storyboards 中
And there's no reason to do this
由于 Storyboards 的引用功能
thanks to storyboard references.
我们不应该这样做
Use a different storyboard file
我们应该为 App 的每个主要部分
for each major section of your
使用不同的 Storyboards 文件
application and then use
然后使用引用功能
references to tie them together.
将它们连接在一起
You'll find it makes it so much
你会发现 这样会使分离单个更改
easier to isolate individual
变得非常容易
changes.
当与更大的团队一起工作时
when working with larger teams,
它也会使事情变得简单得多
as you can avoid the risks of
因为你可以避免
those nasty merge conflicts and
那些讨厌的合并冲突的风险
make resolving those that occur
并且使解决冲突
way easier.
变得更容易
Just like you wouldn't put your
就像你不会将整个源代码
entire source code in a single
放在一个文件中一样
file, don't put your whole UI in
也不要将整个 UI
a single storyboard either.
放在一个 Storyboards 中
Keeping your project file modern
保持项目文件的更新
is a critical way to make sure
是确保 Xcode 能够帮助你解决问题
that Xcode can help you out and
并避免问题积累的
avoids the accumulation of
重要方法
issues.
如果你经常处理的话
can really be a non-issue if you
这些问题实际上
take care of it regularly.
都算不上是问题
But it can really cause problems
但如果你没有经常处理
down the road if you don't keep
在未来的工作中会很容易
up with it.
出现问题
First, when you're updating to a
首先 当你更新到
new version of Xcode, you'll be
Xcode 的新版本时
offered the opportunity
你也有机会让 Xcode
sometimes to have Xcode update
更新项目设置
the project settings and update
并将项目文件
your project file to the latest
更新到最新的格式
format.
因此 除非你有
critical reason not to do this,
重要的理由不更新
we'd recommend that you do it
否则我们建议你在出现提示时选择更新
whenever prompted, or whenever a
或者在问题导航器
warning appears in the issue
中出现警告时进行更新
navigator.
其次 要确保你的项目
project is using the new Xcode
使用的是 2017 年首次发行的
build system first released in
新版 Xcode 构建系统
2017.
它在性能 依赖关系管理方面
improvements in performance,
提供了显著的改进
dependency management, and it's
这对你采用 Swift 包
adoption of Swift packages.
绝对是至关重要的
Now, it's been the default build
自 Xcode 10 起它就是
system since Xcode 10.
默认的构建系统
And you can verify the build
你可以通过查看文件菜单
system that your project is
下的项目设置
using by looking at the project
来验证项目
settings found under the file
正在使用的构建系统
menu.
木工都喜欢保留边角料
onto small scraps, just in case
以备不时之需
we need them someday until that
直到有一天
scrap bin gets so full that we
边角料箱装满
just can't work around it
我们没办法处理它
anymore and we have to come to
我们才不得不接受
terms with the fact that these
这样一个事实
tiny pieces of wood that we've
我们一直保留的边角料
been holding onto are never
永远也无法变成
really going to make it into a
一个真正像样的项目
As developers, we have this
作为开发者
tendency to hold on to scraps,
我们也有保留碎片的习惯
too.
但对我们来说 这个决定更简单
us.
既然你的项目在
under source control, and you do
源代码控制之下
have your project under source
你的项目是在源代码控制之下的
control, right?
对吧
Get rid of that unneeded and
删除那些不需要和
unused code.
不使用的代码
Don't just comment it out just
不要只是把它注释掉
in case you want to pull it back
以防有一天你有用
someday.
如果你真的需要它
it's going to be in the history
它也会在
for that file.
历史文件中
And you can still get it back.
你仍然可以把它拿回来
Let go of those scraps.
扔掉那些碎片吧
Another pile that we really
另一个我们不想
don't want to have grow out of
泛滥成灾的部分就是
control are warnings.
警告
And to that end, establish a
为此 为你自己
zero-warning practice for
和你的团队
yourself and for your team.
建立个没有警告的项目
Code should never be checked in
永远不要在有警告的环境下
that contains warnings.
保留代码
And you should treat warnings as
在编写代码时
errors while you're writing your
应该将警告视为错误
code.
一边做一边修复问题
We've run into projects with
我们碰到过有
thousands of warnings.
上千个警告的项目
And in most cases, they've just
在大多数情况下
accumulated for so long that the
它们积累的时间太长
developer gave up and just never
以至于开发者都放弃了
had time to go fix them all.
根本没有时间去修复它们
Furthermore, if you're
此外 如果你正在
maintaining a project like this,
维护这样的项目
you're not going to see new
当有问题出现时
warnings when they show up.
你不会看到有新的警报
So, this is getting organized.
这个已经整理得挺好了
Keeping a clean workspace and
保持工作空间和项目
project, it's critical to the
整洁有序
long-term health and success of
这对你的 App 的长期健康和成功
your app.
至关重要
So, organize your project with
所以要使用群组来整理项目
groups.
并让这些群组
file system structure.
镜像文件系统结构
Break apart those large
使用引用来分解那些
storyboards using references.
大型 Storyboards
And make sure your project file
还要确保你的项目文件
is up to date.
是最新的
Clean out that old and abandoned
清除旧的和废弃的代码
code and get to the root problem
找到警告的根源
of warnings, and fix them as
并在警告出现时
they arise.
进行修复
Doing these things will make
做这些事情
your project more nimble and
会让的项目更加灵活
your development workflow way
并且在整个项目的生命周期中
better throughout the life of
你的工作进展也会更加
your project.
顺畅
Speaking of source control, one
说到源代码控制
of the things that you should
在设置项目时
always do when you're setting up
你一定要做的事
your project, is enable source
就是启用源代码控制
We do actually come across a lot
我们确实遇到过很多
of projects that don't use
不使用源代码控制的项目
source control, especially those
特别是那些
with solo developer teams.
独立开发团队的项目
Conveniently, when you're
方便的是 当你设置
setting up a new Xcode project,
一个新的 Xcode 项目时
all it takes is to ensure that a
只需要确保
check box is checked and your
选中了一个复选框
project will be under source
你的项目就会用 Git
control using Git.
进行源代码控制了
Now, you can always go back and
现在 当你提交
see what changes you've made in
当前的一组更改时
the past,
你可以回头查看
what's about to change, when you
你在过去做了哪些更改
commit your current set of
以及将要更改的内容
And more easily catch any sort
而且更容易捕捉到
of errors.
任何类型的错误
So, now that you've got Git
因此 现在你已经
enabled, there's a few things
启用了 Git
that you should keep in mind in
为了使它更实用 更高效
order to make it more helpful
你应该牢记一些事情
First, keep your commit small.
首先 保持小的体量
Check your code into your
定期以小的增量
working branch regularly in
将代码签入
small increments.
工作分支
And keep those changes as
并使这些更改
localized and self-contained as
尽可能本地化和自包含
This will give you a path to
当你需要回头查看
look back upon when later on you
或者复原时
need clues or you're trying to
这将为你提供
sort out a regression.
回头查看的路径
And, meanwhile, it's going to
同时 它会降低
reduce your odds of introducing
引入回归的几率
a regression because you're
因为你的改变
making those smaller changes.
都很微小
Second, write useful commit
第二 写有用的提交消息
messages because there comes a
因为总有一天
day when we all ask the question
我们会有一些
that we wish we could answer,
我们希望自己能够回答的问题
what on earth was I thinking?
我当时到底在想什么
Your commit messages are your
当你回忆某些代码
notes to future self when you're
在什么情况下发生了更改
trying to recall under what
以及更改的原因
circumstances some code changed
提交消息就是你
and the reasons why.
对未来自己的注释
Run your source control, like
运行源代码控制
you would for a large team.
就像在大型团队中一样
Even if you were a solo
即便你是一个独立开发者
It means maybe branching for
这意味着可能会
bugs and new features.
出现 Bug 和新特性
And then once you wrap those up,
然后 一旦工作收尾
squash them together back into
将它们压缩回
the main or dev batch, and use a
主批处理或开发批处理中
clean and helpful commit
并要使用一个干净且有用的
message.
提交消息
Now, there are several options
现在 有几个选项和模式
and patterns that you can follow
可以用于
for your source control.
源代码控制
We recommend checking them out
我们建议仔细浏览它们
and finding the one that works
找到一个真正适合你的
really well for you and just
并将其集成到
integrating that into your
你的开发者工作流程中
So, that's tracking.
这就是跟踪
Source control is absolutely
源代码控制对于一个成功的 现代的
critical to a successful, modern
App 开发工作流
app development workflow.
是绝对关键的
So, adopt it as part of your
因此 将其作为项目的一部分
project and embrace it as part
并将其作为
of your regular practice.
常规实践的一部分
Keep those commits small and
保持这些提交短小
write useful commit messages.
并编写有用的提交消息
And finally, utilize branches to
最后 利用分支来帮助
help isolate and manage those
隔离和管理这些更改
changes, bug fixes, and feature
Bug 修复和特性工作
Two of the greatest contributors
在我看来
to clarity and maintainability,
对清晰性和可维护性贡献最大的是
in my opinion, are code comments
代码注释和文档记录
They're a trail of helpful
它们是对你的队友
breadcrumbs for your teammates
或未来的自己
or your future self.
有用的线索
Some might say, "I don't need
有些人可能会说
comments, my code is
我不需要注释 我的代码
self-documenting."
是自我记录的
I don't buy this at all.
我一点也不相信
Well-written code is clear in
写得好的代码
what it's doing algorithmically.
在算法上是清楚的
And it's self-documenting in
在这方面
that respect.
它是自我记录的
But it doesn't convey why.
但我们并不知道原因
Why was this code written in the
为什么一开始要
first place?
写这些代码呢
How does this code fit into the
这段代码如何融入
larger context?
更大的上下文
Nor does it describe the
也没有描述
rationale behind the approach
编写方法
taken when writing it.
背后的原理
The best developers that I work
我共事过的最好的开发者
with, that not only write
不仅写出了令人难以置信的
incredible, clear, and concise
清晰的 简洁的代码
code but they take the time to
而且他们还花时间
sprinkle helpful review comments
在整个代码中
throughout that code, to guide
添加了有用的注释
the future reader into the
引导未来的读者
headspace of the original
进入原作者的空间
Junior developers will likely
初级开发者可能会
benefit from this process, even
从这个过程中受益
more because you're experience
因为你在项目开始时的经验
at the beginning of a project,
与在项目结束时
varies so much from at the end.
相差太大
And the decisions that you make
你在项目开始时所做的决定
at the beginning of a project
实际上可能与项目结束
might actually be at odds with
时所做的决定
the decisions made at the end.
完全不一致
So, what makes for a good
那么 怎样才能做出好的
comment?
提交消息呢
Well, a good comment assumes
好的注释假设读者理解
programming language being used
所使用的编程语言
and can walk through the
并且能够亲历
sequence and steps being taken
代码中的顺序和步骤
And instead, it really focuses
它真正关注的是
on why that code was written in
最初为什么
the first place.
要编写代码
What's the backing for that?
这背后的原因是什么
For example, this is the kind of
例如 这条注释
comment that just doesn't really
没有任何价值
And yet, we see it all the time.
但是 我们总是能看到它
I'm assuming that most of you
假设你们大多数人
have written some code in Swift
已经用 Swift 编写了一些代码
and could just figure out that
可以知道
we're creating a string constant
我们在这里创建了一个
here carrying that value.
带值的字符串常量
But we have no idea what id is,
但我们不知道 id 是什么
what it's used for, or why has
它是用来做什么的
this been hard coded into the
或者为什么这个被硬编码到 App 中
app?
通过一些注释
commenting, we now understand
我们现在理解了
why this value exists and where
为什么存在这个值
it came from.
以及它来自何处
But we can take this one step
但我们可以更进一步
further; names for constants and
常量和变量的名称
variables offer additional
提供了额外的
opportunities for clarity.
清晰的机会
So, if you find yourself using
因此 如果你发现自己使用的是
single letters like m or i, or
m 或 i 这样的单个字母
things like id or idx, it might
或者 id 或 idx 这样的东西
be a great opportunity to choose
那么可能是一个很好的机会
a more descriptive variable
来选择一个更具描述性的变量名
Autocomplete in Xcode works like
在 Xcode 中 自动完成就像魔法一样神奇
So, you don't even really have
所以 你甚至不需要再
to type anything more.
输入任何东西
And it will always be clear
在你的代码库中
throughout your code base what
始终会清楚地知道
particular identifier, in this
在任何时候使用的
case, is being used at any point
特定标识符
in time.
是什么
The benefits to documentation
文档的好处
are very similar to that of
与注释非常相似
But these scale throughout your
但是这些可以扩展到
application and beyond.
整个 App 甚至更远
As you write your own apps,
当你编写自己的 App 时
you're creating layers upon
你正在创建
layers of abstraction and
一层又一层的
algorithms taking what would be
抽象和算法
large and winding passages of
这些抽象和算法
code and breaking them down into
将代码的大段大段地编写出来
tidy, testable, reusable
并将它们分解为整洁的 可测试的 可重用的函数
But if you choose not to
但是如果你
document these functions, you're
不记录这些函数
forcing yourself to actually
那么每次使用该函数时
rewrite that documentation in
你实际上
your mind every single time you
都在强迫自己
go to use that function.
在头脑中重写该文档
Typically, by having to go and
通常 通过必须重新访问
revisit the implementation of
函数的实现
the function, look at how each
查看如何
of the parameters are being
使用每个参数
used, and figure out how it's
并找出如何
going to transform them to
转换它们
provide a result.
以提供结果
In case you aren't aware,
如果你不知道
generating a Dock stub in Xcode
在 Xcode 中生成一个存档
is incredibly easy.
非常简单
Just place your curser on the
只需将光标放在
first line of the function
函数签名的第一行
signature, press option command
按下 Option-Comman-/
slash and all the placeholder
就会自动生成
text you need will be generated
所需的所有
automatically.
占位符文本
Fill in the blanks and you're
只需要填空就好了
done.
点按该函数的任意用法
that function will now bring up
现在就会在你
your own documentation in the
熟悉并喜爱的
same contextual quick help popup
本机 SDK 和 Swift 标准库的上下文
love for the native SDK and
快速帮助弹出窗口中
Swift standard library.
显示你自己的文档
Comments and documentation:
注释和文档
They're one of these really low
要做到它们非常容易
effort but incredibly high
但是非常高回报的
reward investments of your time.
时间投资
And it pays off repeatedly
它会在你的项目的
throughout the life of your
整个生命周期中
So, aid future understanding by
所以 在你的代码中
sprinkling your code with
添加一些有用的注释
helpful comments.
有助于将来的理解
Bring readers into the headspace
用这些注释
of the original author with
把读者带入原作者的
those comments.
思想空间
Use descriptive names for your
对变量使用描述性名称
variables, and fully document
并完整地记录
your functions, properties,
函数 属性
Structs and Enums.
结构和枚举
Next, I'm going to talk about
接下来 我们来聊聊测试
testing, and specifically, unit
特别是单元测试
And to do that, I want to
为此 我想为大家
introduce Marshall.
介绍 Marshall
Marshall is our Swift and
Marshall 是我们 Swift 以及
developer tools evangelist.
开发工具的传播者
He's an incredibly brilliant and
他是个非常聪明
kind fellow.
善良的人
And he also happens to be a
他碰巧也是个
walking, talking Swift-linter.
活生生的 Swift 分析机
Every time I submit my code for
每次我提交代码进行检查时
review, I brace for the tsunami
我都准备好接受
of insightful comments and
大量有深度的注释和反馈
feedback to help me improve what
以帮助我从形式和功能角度
I've written in both form and
改进我的代码
But the other day, Marshall
有一天 Marshall 在另一个主题上
nudged me in the right direction
给了我一个正确的方向
on another topic, unit testing.
那就是单元测试
Now, I must admit, I don't
我必须承认
exactly have an impeccable track
我在编写单元测试方面的纪录
record in writing unit tests.
并不完美
It's not that I don't appreciate
这并不是说
the potential value in them or
我不欣赏他们的潜在价值
that I'm necessarily new to
也不是说我就是新手
It's just I tend to always leave
我只是总习惯
it to last.
把它留到最后
And by the time I've finished
当我完成
implementing the actual code,
实际代码的实现时
the last thing I feel like doing
我最不想做的事情
is writing a unit test.
就是编写单元测试
Nevertheless, the other day,
然而 前几天
while implementing the data
在为 WWDC App
model for the new lab queuing
新的实验室排队功能
feature, in the DubDub app,
实现数据模型的同时
Marshall piped in.
Marshall 加入了进来
&gt;&gt; And while you're doing that,
&gt;&gt; 当你这样做时
you might as well add a unit
你最好再做一个单元测试
test to make sure that the round
来确保在 Struct
trip between the Struct and the
和字典表示之间
dictionary representation keeps
往返的工作能顺利进行
&gt;&gt; Now, in my mind, I really
&gt;&gt;现在 我的大脑
couldn't figure out how this
我真的不知道
would be messed up in the
将来它们会变得多糟糕
But nevertheless, I listened to
尽管如此
Marshall and I put in a simple
我还是听取了 Marshall 的意见
round trip unit test.
行了一个简单的往返单元测试
I ran it.
我测试了
And I felt this significant bit
当绿色的检查标志
of satisfaction when the green
显示测试通过时
check mark showed that the test
我非常有满足感
So, I submitted my changes for
所以 我提交了修改
review and I didn't think about
以供审查
that test again until a couple
直到几周后
of weeks later, when we wanted
当我们想在 Struct 中加入
to include some additional data
额外的数据时
in that Struct.
我才再次考虑这个测试
So, made the changes to the
所以对 Struct
Struct.
做了一些改变
And I didn't see any issues at
我在运行时没有发现
runtime.
任何问题
I'm done, right?
我完成了 对吗
So, went to submit my changes.
于是 我去提交修改
And then I remembered to run
然后 我才想起
that unit test.
运行单元测试
And sure enough, I'd forgotten
果然 我忘了改变
to change how the dictionary
字典反序列化的
deserialization was working and
工作方式
the test caught it.
而测试捕捉到了这一点
The bug would have shown up much
这个 Bug 晚些会
later, when we implementing the
在我们实现 UI 时出现
UI.
而且毫无疑问会
wasted a fair bit of our time,
浪费我们相当多的时间
trying to figure out what went
试图找出问题出在哪里
So, thanks, Marshall, for
所以 谢谢 Marshall 提醒我
reminding me to include unit
将单元测试
tests, as part of my regular
作为我常规实践的
practice.
一部分
&gt;&gt; You're welcome, Josh [brief
&gt;&gt; 不客气 Josh
laughter].
[简短笑声]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; So, even for sections of code
&gt;&gt; 所以 即使对于代码中
that seem deceptively simple, as
看似简单的部分
this particular one did to me at
就像我当时所做的
the time, it's so important to
编写这些单元测试
write those unit tests.
也是非常重要的
With the malleability of code
随着代码的可塑性
comes the potential introduction
可能会引入
of regressions.
回归
And given that we never seem to
考虑到我们似乎
have enough time to test things
从来没有足够的时间来
thoroughly, let's put Xcode to
彻底地测试
work as an extra set of eyes.
就让我们将 Xcode 当作额外的一双眼睛
So, make the implementation of
因此 将单元测试的实现
unit tests a part of your
作为常规开发实践的一部分
regular development practice and
并在每次提交之前
run those tests before each
运行这些测试
Also, unit tests are a key
此外 单元测试也是
component to continuous
持续集成的
integration.
关键组件
So, you can get yourself set up
所以 你可以为它
for that.
做好准备
Tests are another one of these
测试是一个
hidden details that your
隐藏的细节
customers will never actually
你的客户永远不会真正看到
But yet, could mean the
但是 这可能意味着
difference between an incredible
使用你的 App 时的
experience using your app or a
绝佳体验
very frustrating one when some
和重要数据被破坏时
important piece of their data
的糟心体验
has been corrupted.
之间的对比
There's forms of analysis that
大家最好
you'll want to keep as part of
将一些分析形式保留为
your regular workflow.
常规工作流程的一部分
Now, some of these do require
其中一些确实需要一些
some extra time investment.
额外的时间投资
But others can happen for you in
其他的事情
the background without you even
也可能发生在你的幕后
having to think about it.
你甚至不需要去考虑它
One tool that can be very
一个非常有用的工具是
helpful is the Network Link
网络链接调节器
After all, app development tends
毕竟 App 开发
to be performed in homes and
往往是在家庭和办公室进行的
offices with incredible network
对网络性能要求
performance.
非常高
But this really isn't a
但这真的不是一个
representative environment of
你的 App 有可能会运行的
used.
代表环境
So, by enabling the Network Link
所以 通过启动
Conditioner, you can
网络链接调节器
artificially constrain your
你可以人为地
network performance to one
将你的网络性能
similar to that of a typical
压缩至与普通的蜂窝网络
cellular network.
相似的性能
Or even a poorly performing one.
甚至是一个表现不好的性能
You'd be amazed at the number of
你会惊讶于为了让你的用户不必操心
issues that you'll catch with
你需要解决的
loading and race conditions so
加载问题
that you customers don't.
和竞争条件的数量
Inside of your scheme settings,
在你的 Scheme 设置中
there's also several sanitizers
还有好几个检测器和检查器
discover various issues
可以检查你的开发周期内的
throughout your development
各种问题
The Address Sanitizer will watch
Address Sanitizer 会
for things like memory
观察如内存损坏和
corruptions and buffer
缓冲区溢出等问题
Memory issues are frequently the
内存问题经常是
cause of security
安全漏洞的原因
So, using the Address Sanitize,
所以使用 Address Sanitizer
will help you make sure that you
首先可以帮助你
don't ship these is the first
不出现这些问题
By enabling the Thread
通过启用 Thread Sanitizer
Sanitizer, while testing your --
它可以在模拟器中
and debugging your app in the
测试并调试你的 App
simulator, you can help discover
你可以帮助发现这些
data races.
数据竞争
Data races are when you have two
数据竞争是你有两个
threads that are not
不同步的线程
synchronized and at least one of
而它们中至少有一个
those two threads is attempting
试着要编写
to do a write on the same piece
一个相同的数据
Now, these can be particularly
这些可能是非常不好的 Bug
nasty bugs and they can have
它们可能会
programs acting unpredictably.
有些无法预测的程序
Or they can even result in
或者它们也可能会造成
memory corruption.
内存损坏
The Undefined Behavior Sanitizer
Undefined Behavior Sanitizer
captures bugs like dividing by
会捕捉一些如
zero, out of range casts between
除零 浮点溢出 算术溢出
floating point types, overflows,
指针偏差等问题
And when a program has undefined
当一个程序有未定义的行为
behavior, it might cause a
它可能会导致
crash.
崩溃
It might act in unpredictable
它可能会以一种
ways, or it might act like it
无法预测的方式表现
has no problem at all with
或者表现得像毫无问题一样
different results at different
但是会毫无原因地
times seemingly with no reason.
在不同的时间出现不同的结果
Incredibly frustrating bugs; the
这真是令人沮丧的 Bug
sanitizer can help you get rid
检测器可以帮你们
of them, before they can wreak
在它们对你的项目造成大的危害前
havoc on your project.
解决这些 Bug
And finally, there's the Main
最后 还有 Main Thread Checker
Thread Checker which ensures
可以保证
that you're not performing
你没有实现
invalid usage of appKit, UIKit,
AppKit UIKit 和其他 API 的后台线程的
and other API's on background
无效使用
For example, if you're updating
比如说
the UI on a thread other than
如果你在更新一个线程的 UI
the main thread, it can cause
而这个线程不是主线程
missed UI updates, visual
它可能会造成错过的 UI 更新
defects, data corruptions and
视觉缺陷 数据损坏和崩溃
Sometimes these bugs can be
有时候这些 Bug
really hard to track down
可能很难解决
because they might only appear
因为它们可能只会
intermittently.
间歇性出现
Now, there's minimal performance
启用这个会有一个
impact by having this enabled.
最小化的性能影响
So, we just recommend leaving it
我们建议只要可能的话
enabled whenever possible.
都保持其启用状态
While debugging your apps, keep
在调试你们的 App 时
an eye on performance and
注意性能和
resource utilization.
资源使用
And make sure that your app is
尽可能地保证你的 App
being as efficient with system
与系统资源一起
resources as possible.
是有效率的
The first step is, use the Debug
第一步是使用
Gauges.
Debug Gauges
These are found in the debug
当你构建和运行你的项目时
you've built and run your
你就可以在 Xcode 中的调试导航中看到它们
Here you can check out CPU,
你可以在你 App 的生命周期
memory, disk, and network
检查 CPU 内存 磁盘 和网络使用
lifecycle of your app, quickly
快速地了解
understand if your app is doing
你的 App 是否在做
something like connecting to
如通过网络
unexpected servers over the
连接意外的服务器之类的事情
Or maybe it's constantly pulling
或者它只是不断地在一个末端努力
at an end point, and chewing up
消耗很多带宽和电量
And finally, you can take this
最后 你还可以更进一步
even further, by clicking in the
点按文件和工具按钮
profile and instruments button
可以让你运行一个
which will allow you to run an
更加有深度的分析
One particular instrument that I
有一个我常用的工具就是
use a lot is the time profiler.
时间分析器
This allows you to ascertain
这会让你查明
which passages of your code are
你代码的哪一段
taking up the most cycles and
占据了最多的周期
has allowed us to narrow in on
同时也让我们缩小
passages of work that might need
需要同步的
to be made asynchronous.
工作段落
Or perhaps, I just implemented
如果我刚刚实现了一个
in an unscalable manner.
不可拓展的行为
Analysis is a really broad
分析是一个非常宽广的话题
But most of the tools I
但是我这这里提到的大部分
described here only require that
工具你只需要记住
you remember to turn them on.
打开它们即可
So, simulate typical and poor
所以 使用网络链接调节器
networks using that Network Link
来模仿典型的不理想网络
Use those sanitizers and
经常使用检测器和检查器
And just leave them enabled, if
如果可以的话 只需要启动
you can.
它们即可
Refer to those Debug Gauges
定期使用这些
regularly.
Debug Gauges
And just keep an eye on the
注意你 App 的
footprint and performance of
内存占用量和性能
And dig deeper into issues and
通过分析你的 App
address them with great
使用工具
precision, by analyzing your
深入挖掘这些问题
app, using instruments.
用精准度处理它们
Turning these small efforts into
把这些努力转变为习惯
habits will go a long way into
会很大程度地
improving the performance and
改善你们 App 的
reliability of your apps.
性能和稳定性
Back when I lived in Toronto, I
我住在多伦多的时候
had a single car garage that I
我把一个车库
had converted into my
改成了我的
woodworking shop.
木工商店
It was a cozy space.
这是一个舒适的地方
And I had it entirely to myself.
这完全属于我自己
But since moving to the Bay
但是自从我搬到
Area, I don't have a space to
海湾地区 我就不再拥有一个
myself anymore.
属于我自己的空间了
And I've been using various
我开始使用
shared and community woodshops
这片地区共享的
in the area.
社区木工房
Now, doing so can be a bit
这样有时候会很令人沮丧
frustrating at times because now
因为我必须
I have to share the tools and
和其他人共享
the equipment and the space with
工具和设备以及空间
But something I hadn't realized
但是有一件事我没有意识到
I would appreciate so much is
我会如此感激的是
the opportunity to bounce ideas
我可以在店里
off of others in the shop.
听取他人的意见
And get their opinions on ways
获得他们的意见
to go about doing things.
可以开始做一些事情
I think with app development the
我认为 App 开发
analog here is that of code
与之类似的就是
review.
代码审核
So, for many of the apps I've
所以很多我过去开发的 App
built over the years, I've been
都只有我一个开发者
And much like having your own
这就好像拥有你自己的商店
shop, it feels incredibly fast
感觉非常地快速和灵活
and nimble because only your own
因为你的想法
opinion matters.
决定了一切
But the drawback is that you
但是缺点就是
don't have that opportunity to
你没有机会
learn from your colleagues and
向你的同事和同行
peers on better ways to use the
学习如何更好地
language, frameworks, and SDK.
使用语言 框架和 SDK
Often, although there's lots of
一般来说 解决问题
ways to approach a problem,
有很多方法
there's often a better way.
但是总会有一个更好的办法
Something that stands out in
有些方法脱颖而出是因为
terms of being more concise.
更加精准
Or maybe is more -- has greater
或者有更好的
performance, maintainability or
性能 可维护性或可靠性
Because, after all, just because
因为如果只是因为它能运行
it works, doesn't mean that it's
并不能代表
necessarily right.
它是完全正确的
Or that it could somehow be
它可能可以
significantly improved.
获得很大的提升
At Apple, all teams have a
在 Apple  所有团队都有一个政策
policy where no code makes it
那就是如果没有代码审核
into a project without code
那么没有一个代码能成为
review.
一个项目
Our team has learned so much
我们的团队通过
from each other through this
这个方法从彼此身上
process.
学到了很多
And our code is way more
我们的代码在风格上也更一致
alone the improvements in the
更别说在可靠性上的提升了
It also ensures that our entire
这也保证了
team is more familiar with a
我们的整个团队更了解
broader set of the code base,
更广泛的代码基数
allowing the range of bugs and
这使得我们可以
features that we can each tackle
解决的 Bug 范围和特点
to be much wider.
也更加广泛
Now, I have this fortune of
现在 我很幸运
being on a great team of
能加入一个拥有很多有经验的
experienced developers, which
开发者的好团队
makes this much simpler.
这也让这些更加的简单
But what if you're running a
但是如果你自己开了公司
company on your own or are the
或者你们项目
sole developer on your project?
只有你一个开发者怎么办呢
Well, try to find a way to
你可以试着
connect with fellow developers
与你们地区的开发者联系
in your area or from around the
或者与世界各地的其他开发者联系
And come up with a way to do a
想办法和他们互相
code review exchange with them.
进行代码审核
Maybe investigate meet-ups,
也许是调查见面会
local conferences, and
本地会议
co-working spaces.
或者共享办公
So, now that you're going to do
现在你要做的就是把代码审核
code review, as part of your
作为你开发实践的一部分
development practice, what makes
那么什么是一个好的
a great code review?
代码审核呢
Well, first, it means taking the
首先 它意味着
time to understand each changed
花时间了解
line of code.
每一行变化的代码
There's no point in doing a code
如果只是快速浏览的话
review if it's just a quick
就代码审核就
skim.
没有意义
Second, actually build the
其次 真正地构建这个项目
Run it. Don't assume that the
运行这个项目 不要假设
original author actually did
原始的作者已经
this.
这样做过
Especially if the last commit
尤其是如果
you see in the history was a
你在历史中看到的最后一个任务是合并
Run those tests.
运行这些测试
First, doing so reminds you to
首先 这样做会提醒你
check and see that there are
去检查和看看
actually tests.
真正的测试
And that the unit tests pass.
以及通过的单元测试
Remember, that just because it
记住 仅仅是因为它构建了
builds doesn't mean that it's
不能代表它就
not broken somehow.
不会崩溃了
Read those comments and
仔细看看这些注释和文档
I mean, there are comments and
我的意思是 总会有
documentation, right?
注释和文档 对吗
And then look for spelling and
然后检查拼写和语法错误
Similarly, look for spelling
与此相似的
errors in variable names.
在变量名中寻找拼写错误
So, as a Canadian, I have this
作为一个加拿大人
long-standing habit of including
我一直有一个习惯
"u" in words like colour, which
就是在如“color”等单词中添加“u”
drives my team absolutely nuts,
当我的团队开始搜索“color”时
when they go and search for
他们真的要崩溃了
Ensuring consistency in the code
保证代码基数的
base helps with finding and
一致性可以在之后
using these functions and
帮助寻找和使用
variables later on.
这些功能和变量
And again, it just saves time.
这还是会节省时间
So, even though it might feel
所以 即便你可能会感觉
like this process is slowing you
这些过程可能会
down in the short-term, it will
在短期内拉慢你的项目
undoubtedly save you time,
但是长期来看 它通过减少
money, and customers in the
潜在的错误和问题
future through the reduction of
它毫无疑问会节约
potential errors and issues in
你的时间 金钱和
the long-run.
用户成本
And your skills, as a developer,
如果你在未来使用相似的方法
will benefit significantly, when
或挑战的话
you approach similar patterns or
你作为开发者的技能
challenges in the future.
会大受裨益
As developers, we're all
作为开发者 我们都致力于
endeavoring to create small,
创建精简的
refined, reusable and testable
准确的 可重复使用的
sections of code.
可测试的代码
After all, we don't want to have
毕竟 我们不想
to constantly recreate the same
不停地重新创造
code over and over.
相同的代码
Packages and frameworks offer an
程序包和框架
opportunity to maintain that
可以用更集中的方式
code in a more centralized way.
保留代码
And offer that functionality in
同时以一种可移植的方式
a portable fashion.
提供那个性能
Not only through your current
它不仅会通过你现在的 App
app, but through other apps that
还会通过其他
might be able to leverage that
可能会利用这个成就的 App
effort.
来提供
If your app includes extensions,
如果你的 App 包含拓展
by packaging up your shared code
你可以在框架中
between -- in a framework, your
打包你的共享代码
binary size will actually reduce
你的二进制大小可能会减小
because both your main app and
因为你的主 App
your extensions can actually
和拓展都会
share that same framework.
分享相同的框架
Of course, creating packages
当然了 创造程序包会让你
also offers the opportunity to
有机会与
share your efforts with the
整个社群分享
community especially with the
你的成就
tight integration now found in
尤其是现在的 Xcode 11
Xcode 11.
对此有如此深度的集成
But even more than the code that
为了便于他人使用
lives in your app, shared
你的 App 中不仅是代码
frameworks, packages, and
共享的框架 程序包和库
by great documentation, in order
都需要很好的文档
So, embrace packages and
所以 采用程序包
frameworks as a way to break
和框架是打散
apart your code base.
你的代码的一个办法
This will also allow you to
这还会让你
scale your work across multiple
扩大你的工作至
apps you might be working on and
你可能在开发或维护的
maintaining.
多个 App 中
Frameworks can help you reduce
框架还可以帮你减小
the binary size.
二进制文件大小
And then you can, of course,
然后你就可以
share your efforts with the
与社群共享你的
community.
成就
But be sure to include that
但是请保证
great documentation.
其包含了很好的文档
The last area that I want to
今天我想和你们分享的
talk to you about today is
最后一点就是
dependencies, and, specifically,
依赖 明确点就是
understanding the benefits and
了解它们可能会给你的项目
risks of bringing them into your
带来的好处和风险
Using Swift packages,
使用 Swift 程序包
frameworks, and other libraries,
框架和其他函数库
offers many benefits.
会有很多好处
But before you start to use a
在你开始使用
given package, it's really
规定的程序包前
important to know what's inside
知道里面有什么
of it.
以及它可能会
And what could be potentially
带来什么
coming along for the ride.
真的很重要
Make sure that you understand
你需要确保自己了解
what your dependency is doing
你的依赖和数据
with data.
会产生什么
Ultimately, you're responsible
根本上来说 你需要
for the contents of your app.
对你 App 的内容负责
And what it's doing with user
以及它对用户数据所做的负责
Make sure that the framework
确保框架没有
isn't collecting metrics or
收集不必要的
device information that's
指标和设备信息
And make sure that it's
确保它没有
definitely not sending that data
从设备发送数据
Note what other dependency, a
注意其他的依赖
giving dependency, depends on.
一个给定的依赖性 依靠的是什么
And research into those, as
同时研究它们
After all, including a
毕竟多层依赖
means that your app is actually
现在意味着你的 App
riding on the security and
实际上取决于
success of that entire chain.
整个链的安全和成功
And, finally, there's one other
最后 还有另一个其他的可能性
What if the framework breaks on
如果框架在你这崩溃了
you?
怎么办
What if it becomes unmaintained?
如果它没有维护了怎么办
Or what if it just disappears?
或者它就是突然不见了怎么办
It's really important to have a
当你为你的项目
plan on how you're going to deal
引入一个新的依赖时
with each of these situations
重要的是
anytime you're introducing a new
有一个如何解决
dependency into your project.
这些情况的计划
After all, your applications
毕竟 你的 App 的
future is now dependent on it.
未来依赖于此
So, are you going to be able to
所以 你要自己修复
fix the open bugs yourself?
这些公开的 Bug 吗
Are you going to bring that
你要把项目带回内部
project in-house and maintain
然后维护它吗
Or are you going to plan to have
或者你计划
to completely swap out that
在之后把那个依赖
dependency later?
完全替换掉
With all of the necessary work
与所有和那个任务一起的
that comes with that task?
必要的工作一起吗
The use of external
外部依赖的使用
dependencies, such as Swift
比如 Swift 程序包
packages, can allow you to move
可以让你进展更快
more quickly and avoid
同时避免
recreating tools that might
重新创建在社群中
already exist in the community.
可能已经存在的工具
But be diligent in their use.
但是要注意它们的使用
Ensure that they only do what
保证它们只做
you expect them to.
你让它们做的事情
And absolutely ensure that they
一定要确保
respect the privacy of people
它们会尊重使用你 App 的
using your apps.
用户的隐私
Make sure you establish that
确保你有一个计划
plan of what you're going to do
来应对未来
if they break or otherwise go
如果它们崩溃
away in the future.
或者消失的情况
If you make answering these
如果在你为项目
questions a habit when adding a
增加新的依赖时
new dependency to your project,
能把问这些问题当成一个习惯
it's going to payoff in the long
长远来看你将获得回报
run, and maximize the benefits
同时会最大化
of using them.
使用它们的好处
With app development projects,
对于 App 开发项目来说
it can sometimes feel like the
有时候完成它最后的 10%
last 10% of the project takes
似乎和最初的
just as long as the first 90% of
90% 一样漫长
But I think that by trying to
但是我认为
convert some of these practices
通过试着转变某些操作
and principles into habits, you
和规则为习惯
can help avoid that feeling.
你可以避免那种感觉
So, by effectively organizing
所以 有效地组织
your workspace, you can work
你的工作空间 你可以
faster and more efficiently
更快且更有效地
keeping focused on the actual
把注意力集中在代码上
Through the power of source
借助强大的源代码控制
control, you can track your code
你可以准确地
base with precision, reduce the
追踪你的代码基数
odds of regressions, and
减少回归的几率
expedite the investigation of
加快发现可能发生的
bugs that might occur.
Bug 的速度
By writing helpful and
通过写下有用的
meaningful comments and
有意义的注释和文档
documentation, you can reduce
你可以在未来重新访问代码
you revisit code in the future
和利用你构建的
and every time you make use of a
类 结构和功能时
class, Struct, or function that
减少理解的压力
Unit tests will save you at the
单元测试每 11 个小时
eleventh hour, from checking
会保存一次
encode that introduces new
通过检查引入
regressions.
新回归的编码
Sanitizers and checkers offer
检测器和检查器
ongoing analysis of your code
不停地对你的代码进行分析
and they run in the background
因为它们在后台运行
without you even having to think
你甚至都不需要去
about it.
担心它们
Gauges and instruments ensure
传感器和工具
that you are being efficient
保证你有效地
with your use of system
使用系统资源
resources and they'll allow you
它们会让你
to chase down performance and
准确地找出性能和
other issues, with precision.
其他问题
Code review is not only a chance
代码审核不仅仅
to evaluate the style and
是一个评估你代码
function of your code, but an
风格和功能的机会
enormous learning opportunity
也是一个学习开发的很好的机会
for developing -- for evolving
它可以提升你作为
your skills as a developer and
开发者的技能
sharing them with your team and
与你的团队和社群分享
Breaking your projects into
将你的项目
smaller and reusable packages
分解成更小的和可重复使用的程序包
and frameworks can help scale
以及框架
your work across multiple
可以帮助你扩大你的工作
projects and allow you to share
至多个项目 并让你能够分享它
There's also those benefits to
对于二进制文件的大小
binary size.
也有所裨益
And finally, the use of external
最后 外部依赖
dependencies, such as Swift
如 Swift 程序包的使用
packages, can help you move more
可以让你进展更快
quickly and reuse functions that
同时可以重复使用
might already exist in the
已经在社群存在的函数
But be diligent in their use.
一定要认真使用
Understand what they do with
理解它们如何处理
user data.
用户数据
And establish a plan in case
设定一个计划
they go away.
以防止它们消失
Including these practices as
作为 App 开发者 将这些实践作为
part of your work as an app
你工作的一部分
developer will only add a small
只会增加
bit of time to each phase of
你项目每个阶段的
your project.
一点点时间
But it will save you an
但是从长远来看
incredible amount of time, over
它会为你节省很多时间
the long run, ensuring your app
保证你的 App
is built to last.
能运行久远
I hope that this collection of
我希望我今天提供给你们的
ideas and suggestions I've
想法和建议
offered you today, has allowed
可以让你们思考
you to think about how you too
作为一名 App 开发者
can further improve your craft
如何更好地
as an app developer.
提升你们的技能
Practices you might incorporate
你可能会养成习惯的的操作
to allow you to raise the
会增加你工作的
quality and durability of your
质量和持久性
work and conscious efforts that
有意识的努力
you can turn into automatic
可以转化为自动的习惯
habits, that allow you to direct
它可以让你把自己的能量
your energy to the areas of most
用到最重要的地方
For the people who engage with
那些使用你 App 的人
your apps will feel that care
会感受到你为之倾注的
and love that you've poured into
关怀与爱
your work even if they can't
即便他们也说不出
exactly say why.
为什么
And you can take great pride in
你也可以为你创造出的东西
what you have crafted.
感到自豪
Thank you.
谢谢
[ Applause ]
[掌声]